I'm not sure if you can see it or not
I've got a little bit of a sunburn on my
face I'm working on it
you know I'd be smart enough to put
sunscreen on my kids apparently not on
myself
I know enough orphan drugs out there I
guess that a little bit of melanoma I'm
willing to roll the dice with so I've
greased up my face and considering I
didn't insure my face the way I should
open gates the harsh harsh UV rays of
the light I've decided to talk about
some life insurers too in fact this is
going to be a first for Wall Street
breakdowns we're going to do two
earnings calls in one two major Canadian
insurers they announced earnings today
that's Manulife Financial the biggest
Canadian insurer and sunlight financial
the third biggest Canadian insurer
now if you were to go into a financial
advisor you have anybody in your life
whatsoever including yourself you're
still not working I'm not going to get
into all of it you know what speak to
your financial advisor but I can assure
you that something like life insurance
while I'm going to talk about a few
other things I don't like with these
companies despite really good earnings
calls from Manulife and Sun Life I'm not
a big fan of investing through companies
like these but investing in companies
like these might be a little different
through companies like these hmm kind of
not my thing but you know what any good
financial advisors are doing is proper
due diligence is going to cover the
bases with you on life insurance long
before they cover any bases on investing
that's just the way a good financial
advisor works they're making sure that
their client is taken care of for any
unforeseen anything that might crop up
in the future you can never predict that
I can tell you things will happen it's
best to plan for them companies like
Manulife Financial and Sun Life
Financial they do an excellent job of
ensuring that people are as well taken
care of as the insurance they choose to
purchase I suggest purchasing wisely
anyways Manulife Financial announced
earnings today EPS came at 57 cents a
share
that beat the street by two cents that
beat last year's quarter last record was
only 40 cents a share so that's not bad
they attribute a lot of that to growth
in Asia the strong growth in Asia was up
187 million that's pretty good for
Manulife Financial they're definitely
spreading their wings and getting out
there but their investment gains also
grew 154 million this is where it gets a
little sticky for me some of the money
that they made was from higher fee
income from wealth and asset management
business you know what that means
they're charging you more money they're
charging you more money they're MFD a
fact of the matter is is they're selling
you they're selling you a lot of
proprietary mutual funds those have high
em ers they make a lot of money on that
stuff just not the way I would go do
your due diligence in your research make
sure that when you do sit down with an
advisor they can offer you all the
options why do I care that you're only
nm FDA and you could only give me mutual
funds that's not my problem that sounds
like a your licensing problem not on my
options problem I want a professional I
want a professional that can do
everything and if he's not the
professional that knows specifically
what to do that I want him to know
someone who knows that he can refer me
to I don't want a company that's selling
a lot of stuff bundled together like
everybody else is making all their money
off of fees that kind of irks me Mannie
life is up though
good for you manual life good for you
son life is not even better than that
son life was up there earnings per share
was 93 cents that beat the street by
four last year was 78 cents so they beat
the street and they beat last year but
their earnings per share this quarter if
you take away any kind of one-off items
you exclude any kind of payments they
might have had balloon payments anything
that
do a bond corporate bond something had
to be paid out dollar twelve beat the
street by fifteen cents that's
remarkable the street estimated 97 cents
they came in a dollar twelve they've
missed estimates two quarters in a row
now this is a big beat the CEO mentioned
this the earnings call he said investors
gotta like this I like this too that's
that's a you're running a good company
some way financial and Manulife are
great companies they're well run again
would I invest in companies similar to
this these companies specifically please
consult your licensed professional
financial adviser but what I invest in
companies in this area yes because a lot
of people do bring their money to
companies like this and allow these
companies to do far more work than just
insurance but what I recommend having
your broker be one of the guys that work
here think things through do all your
due diligence keep all your options open
options are a marvelous thing to have I
don't think Manulife or Sun Life would
even let you buy options for a while you
know anything about options there you go
they missed expectations in two straight
quarters and in this quarter they blew
it out of the water I would say Sun Life
and Manulife both had amazing earning
calls both of them with substantial
growth in Asia actually someone's
mentioned I think 77 million in Asia
this year versus 68 million in Asia last
year
there you go Canada two of your three
major insurance providers are doing
excellent thanks to you they should
definitely be thanking you they didn't
get to the one in three position if it
wasn't for all the Canadians that pay
into Manulife and Sun Life if you use
one of these companies just as an aside
next time you walk into your brokers
office or next time he comes to Euro so
now it's you questions about what what
you want to do this year
things go under how the kids are doing
ask my Manulife made so much money off
of fees ask why some of those fees
aren't then passed back down to you if
you've been a client maybe for a long
period of time Manulife made money on
fees they made money on a lot of other
stuff doing a good job growing pretty
limited to be charging all that money
just my opinion please do your research
do your due diligence speak to a
licensed professional financial advisor
don't take information from me you don't
know that I don't not just beef with the
people that work at Immanuel law reform
orchard I don't actually have any beef
with them they run an awesome company I
just love options when it comes to being
able to invest in different stuff and
not have to buy proprietary things that
are kind of under the umbrella of that
company and then they still charge me a
whole bunch of money I don't like paying
a bunch of money I'm trying to make a
bunch of money so paying you a bunch of
money doesn't really do me a lot
Manulife beat on earnings beat on
estimates beat it all sonlife did the
same growth in Asia Canada that's
insurance for you